Trần Minh Hiếu

Full-stack Developer

📞 0962043769 屋 hieu243910@gmail.com 🙋 https://github.com/hieu4399243 👂 Phạm Văn Đồng, Bắc Từ Liêm, Hà Nội

INTRODUCTION

I am a software engineer who started as a Back-end Developer but felt that Front-end was more aesthetically pleasing, so I tried my hand at Front-end Developer. With nearly 2 years of experience in software engineering, I work in many fields, including Front-end fields such as Websites, Mobile apps, and Back-ends such as Java, .Net, PHP, and a little experience in Devops field. In addition, during the working process, I studied and worked I also took on the position of tester for the team along with taking on the position of Scrum master for team development. I hope to work in a professional technology environment and always do my best for the company and the products I participate in.

EDUCATION

FPT Ha Noi University

2019 - 2023

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Degree: Good

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web4S 02/2022 - 02/2023

PRODUCT ENGINEER

Front-end Developer

- Participate in the Website design team, working directly according to customer requests.
- Requirements Analysis.
- Responsive Design, build Modules corresponding to previously designed requirements or Websites requested by customers.
- Communicating with Testers, customers, and the company's business team.

Back-end Developer

- Join the team to build systems for the company and provide consulting services to customers.
- My job in this phase is to assign user rights, send purchase confirmation emails to customers, Reconcile, Admin Service, Customer Quotation.

The techniques, tools, and languages that I use during my work:

Programming language: PHP

- · Back-end framework: Cake PHP 4
- Database management system: MySQL
- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Smarty
- CRM Website manager tasks, Gitlab to manager source code.

Greenify Việt Nam 04/2023 - 12/2023

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Front-end Developer

- Participate in system development, building interfaces for websites or apps.
- The main job is to build applications according to customer requirements,
- Perform functions such as:push notifications, user data management, chatbox, shopping.

The techniques, tools, and languages that I use during my work:

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, React Native
- Github to manager source code, Jira, Slack

CER	TIF	[<i>C</i> \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \ \	$\Gamma \Gamma \cap$	PIK
v aran				

CERTIFICATIONS		
User Experience Research	ch and Design - Cousera	June 2023
Software Development Lifecycle - Cousera		January 2022
Entrepreneurship Capstone - Cousera		November 2022
CertNexus Certified Ethical Emerging Technologist - Cousera		June 2022
Web Design for Everybody: Basics of Web Development & Coding - Cousera		October 2021
Computer Communications - Cousera		June 2021
Academic Skills for Uni	versity Success - Cousera	April 2021
SKILLS		
Java	Java Core and ObjectOriented Programming (OOP), Mu Spring Cloud, Spring Security, Microservices	Itithreading and Concurrency, Spring Boot,
C#	.Net Core, Entity Framework	
PHP	PHP core, Cake PHP	
Front-end	ReactJs, Javascript, TypeScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Ta	ailwind
Mobile	React Native, Android studio	
VCS	Github, GitLab	
Database	MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB	
CI/CD	Jenkins, SonarQube	
Kubernetes	Argo-cd, Kibana	
Tester	Manual testing, Automation testing	
Japanese	N4	
English	Reading comprehension	
Scrum Master	Jira	

PROJECTS

Name of customer	FPT University
Description project	FPTUPay is an e-wallet project aimed at enhancing services for students at FPT University campuses. The project offers fast and convenient money transfer, deposit, withdrawal, and school fee payment services. It addresses the issue of withdrawing money from FAP to the wallet, allowing the school's bonuses for students to be directly transferred to the wallet without the need for application or waiting. The project employs microservices and utilizes Java for backend development and JavaScript for mobile and frontend development. The environment is run on Kubernetes (k8s) and includes built-in tools such as Rancher, ELK, Grafana, Longhorn, Kafka, Jenkins, Sonarqube, Argo-cd, Minio, Harbor (Registry), and Debezium to support operations. FPTUPay is poised to provide superior student services and is the first university in Vietnam to have its own e-wallet.
My team size	5
Resource	https://github.com/fptupay/mobile-app.git
My responsibility in project	Back-end, Front-end, Scrum Master, Tester
Technology description	Service: Ewallet (Finance, User, Job, ETL, Merchant, Gateway,), EKY-C, OTP, Storage, IAM Tools: Java, Spring Boot, Microservices, Kubenertes, Docker, ELK, APM, Debezium, Kafka, Redis, Jenkins, Sonarqube, Argo-cd, Minio, Harbor(Register, Docker Hub), Longhorn, Rancher, Cert-manager, SFTP, Mysql, ReactJS, React Native.

Toan Cham Restaurant

(05/2023 - 06/2023)

Name of customer	Toan Cham Restaurant
Description project	Create a beautiful and user-friendly website for a restaurant, where customers can view the menu, choose dishes, choose the menus they want to order and then contact the restaurant via zalo or phone number. phone. The product uses technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
Your team size	1
Resource	https://toan-cham-restaurant-azure.vercel.app/
Your responsibility in project	Front-end
Technology description	HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Dating app

(12/2023 - 03/2024)

Name of customer	Dating app
Description project	The application is created to find suitable subjects for you, based on logging in, authenticating users through registered email, searching for users through information and corresponding indicators. The application is written in React Native, data is saved on MoongoDB.
Your team size	1
Resource	https://github.com/hieu4399243/Dating-app.git
Your responsibility in project	Back-end, Front-end
Technology description	React Native, MoongoDB, Socket IO, ExpressJS

Travel app

(05/2023 - 06/2023)

Name of customer	Travel app
Description project	The application provides experience about the tourism industry, to search and view details of travel service packages.
Your team size	1
Resource	https://github.com/hieu4399243/travel-native.git
Your responsibility in project	Front-end
Technology description	React Native, Yup, Formik

Spotify app

(05/2023 - 06/2023)

Name of customer	Spotify app
Description project	The app is adapted from the Spotify app, using StepZen to call the API via GraphQL.
Your team size	1
Resource	https://github.com/hieu4399243/SpotifyVersion2.git
Your responsibility in project	Front-end
Technology description	React Native, StepZen, GraphQL

FPTCMS-NET

(06/2023 - 07/2023)

Name of customer	FPTCMS
Description project	Website provided for FPT university students, with tasks such as taking attendance, checking subjects, and viewing detailed student information. Website uses framework from .net and manages data through SQL.
Your team size	1
Resource	https://github.com/hieu4399243/FPTCMS-Net.git
Your responsibility in project	Back-end, Front-end
Technology description	.Net, Html, Css, Jquery, Sql, Ajax

CONTACTS

Github: https://github.com/hieu4399243

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100077935690670

Zalo: 0962043769